userlytics.com 2019-12-05

# Privacy Policy - Clients

Effective Date: January 08, 2018

This Privacy Policy explains what information of yours will be collected by USERLYTICS™ CORPORATION and its subsidiary company (User Testing International SL) when you access the Sites and/or create an account at USERLYTICS™ as a tester, how that information will be used, and how you may exercise your rights of collection, correction and/or deletion of information. By using the Services, you consent that Your information is processed in accordance with this Policy. 

We will not use or share your personal information with anyone except as described in this document. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect through offline sources. All information collected through our forms and other online sources shall be limited to the purposes explained in this Privacy Policy. 

### Here are the types of information we gather:

**Information you give us:** we receive and store any information you provide us when you complete our forms or when you decide to accept an invitation to participate in a test. 

**Automatic Information:** we automatically receive and store certain types of information when you use USERLYTICS™,including your interaction with our website.

### For what purposes?

**Offering services to our clients:** we offer usability and user experience testing services to our clients, as well as other types of market research services, and may share information about you and the tests done by you with our clients.

**Improving our services:** we may use some of the information to improve our site and our services.

**Marketing and commercial purposes:** we may use information, we collect, including audiovisual recordings of your interactions during tests that you decided to participate in, to promote our services, by publishing videos or images with your face, screen or audio on our public website.

**Communicate with you:** We may use your personal information to communicate with you about USERLYTICS™.

### 1\. Information We Collect.

  * a) When you **create an account** as a client or submit a form: we may collect personally identifiable information about you, such as your full name, your phone number, your IP, your email address, and other related information such as pages visited (with the IP, location and time) and other information about your activities like email bounces, when you open an email we sent to you, or when you subscribe/unsuscribe from our marketing campaigns.

  * b) When you **login** with your client account, we may collect information about your browser, operating system and your IP. 

  * c) When you **submit a test:** we may collect information about the test you have created, such as: the name of the test, metrics and results and your test script. 

  * d) **Cookies and Tracking Technologies:** we use technologies such as: cookies, parameters, and scripts. These technologies are used for different goals such as: affiliate systems, remarketing, retargeting or analytics studies. These technologies may be used in analyzing trends, administering USERLYTICS™ websites or client websites, tracking users movements around the site, knowing where a visitor comes from, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

We also use cookies for remembering user setting configurations, as well as for authentication and analytics. Users can configure the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our website, but some areas or features may be limited.

This website uses **Google Analytics** , an analytics tool by Google Inc, to track user activity, page content, time on page, tree maps, and other related data.

Also this site uses **Hotjar** , an analytics tool, to track user behavior, like clicks, scroll usage, and screenshot and recordings of the browser screen activities, as well as **AgileCRM** , which tracks emails activities like email bounces or number of opened emails, and also tracks user activities in USERLYTICS™.

### 2\. How We Use Your Information. 

We use the information we collect to operate and maintain our professional services, also we may use the information in order to contact you, send marketing campaigns or materials, inform you about new features or capabilities, send you newsletters or answer your questions about our platform or your account.

### 3\. How We Share Your Information.

  * **a) Personally Identifiable Information:** We may store personal information in locations outside the direct control of USERLYTICS™ (for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers). USERLYTICS™ may share information that identifies you personally ONLY in the following circumstances: 

    * **1)** Such information is being featured on any of the USERLYTICS™ public pages as testimonials or cases studies. USERLYTICS™ will not publish this information without prior permission from you. 

    * **2)** USERLYTICS™ or any relevant business unit is or may be acquired by a third party; 

    * **3)** USERLYTICS™ is under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any valid legal process, such as subpoenas, search warrants and court orders, or other valid law enforcement obligations, or to protect itself or others, or establish or exercise its legal rights or defend against legal claims.

    * **4)** Although we do not control the behaviour of the participants that are invited to interact with test assets you may define as part of a project, and said participants are not employees of USERLYTICS™, USERLYTICS™ testers do agree to a Terms of Use Agreement with USERLYTICS™, including non-disclosure and confidentiality provisions, in relation to keeping test assets and tests confidential, and to prevent unauthorized copying of said test assets. 

  * **b) Non-Personally Identifiable Information:** we may share information _ONLY_ in the following circumstances: 

    * **1)** USERLYTICS™ may extract statistics and other non-personally identifiable information from the tests and reports you have created, and/or pass them on to third parties for marketing or other purposes.

    * **2)** USERLYTICS™ or any relevant business unit is or may be acquired by a third party;

    * **3)** USERLYTICS™ is under a duty to disclose or share this kind of data in order to comply with any valid legal process, such as subpoenas, search warrants and court orders, or other valid law enforcement obligations, or to protect itself or others, or establish or exercise its legal rights or defend against legal claims.

### 4\. Data Transfers to Third Parties

**Third-Party Agents or Service Providers.**  
We may transfer Personal Data to third-party agents or service providers who perform functions on our behalf. Where required by the Privacy Shield, we enter into written agreements with those third-party agents and service providers requiring them to provide the same level of protection that Privacy Shield requires and limiting their use of the data to the specified services provided on our behalf. We take reasonable and appropriate steps to ensure that third-party agents and service providers process Personal Data in accordance with our Privacy Shield obligations and to stop and remediate any unauthorized processing. Under certain circumstances, we may remain liable for the acts of our third-party agents or service providers who perform services on our behalf for their handling of Personal Data that we transfer to them.

**Disclosures for National Security or Law Enforcement**  
Under certain circumstances, we may be required to disclose your Personal Data in response to valid requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

### 5\. Storage and Processing. 

Your information collected through the USERLYTICS™ Service may be stored and processed in the United States or Europe.

Your data will only be transferred within the EU or the US (and ONLY to 3rd parties that are subscribed to the EU-US PRIVACY SHIELD agreement). Therefore, your data will NEVER be transferred to third countries that do not have the same level of protection as agreed by the GDPR.

### 6.How long do we keep your personal information?

We keep your personal information to enable your continued use of USERLYTICS™, for as long as required in order to fulfil the relevant purposes described in this Privacy Notice.

### 7\. How We Protect Your Information.

All information you provide to USERLYTICS™ is stored on secure servers. Any payment transactions will be encrypted using _SSL_ technology. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of any usernames or passwords associated with any account that you use to provide the testing services, and for monitoring all activity under your account. 

You may not disclose or share your username or password with any third parties or use them for any unauthorized purpose. You shall be deemed responsible and you agree to assume full responsibility for all activities, acts or omissions of anyone that occur under your account.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although USERLYTICS™ will use reasonable efforts to protect your personal data, it cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted over the Internet. Any transmission is at your own risk. Once USERLYTICS™ has received your information, it will use reasonable procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorized access.

### 8\. Privacy Shield. (US & EU)

USERLYTICS™ complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. USERLYTICS™ has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. 

To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov ](https://www.privacyshield.gov/)

  * USERLYTICS implements the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice; Choice; Accountability for Onward Transfer; Security; Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation; Access; and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability in processing your Personal Data. 
  * In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, USERLYTICS™ commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy _should first contact Userlytics at dpo@userlytics.com_
  * USERLYTICS™ has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles to the **INSIGHTS ASSOCIATION PRIVACY SHIELD PROGRAM** , a nonprofit alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States and operated by the Insights Association. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, please contact or visit [Insights Association complaint](https://www.insightsassociation.org/get-support/privacy-shield-program/privacy-shield-eu-swiss-citizens-file-complaint) for more information or to file a complaint. The services of Insights Association are provided at no cost to you. 
  * With respect to Personal Data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield framework, USERLYTICS™ is **subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the US Federal Trade Commission and/or the Department of Transportation.**
  * Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield Website, you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted. 
  * Userlytics is also registered with the [ICO of the United Kingdom](https://ico.org.uk/) and our registration reference is: ZA465454 

### 9\. Compromise of Personal Information. 

In the event that personal information is compromised as a breach of security, USERLYTICS™ will promptly notify our clients in compliance with applicable law. 

### 10\. Data Access, Correction, Deletion, and Opt Out.

You can review all the information we collected from you by contacting us directly at dpo@userlytics.com

You can correct or update all the information we collected from you by contacting us directly at dpo@userlytics.com, you can also update some of the information in your profile dashboard.

You can request to stop receiving emails or direct communications from Userlytics, by clicking on the unsubscribe link on your email and following the indicated steps or by contacting us directly at dpo@userlytics.com.

You can request to remove all of your personal information by contacting us directly at dpo@userlytics.com or by indicating said intent in your profile dashboard. However, We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide our services, and when this information is necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.

In summary, you have the right to request access to, correct, and delete your personal data, in relation to data that is not being provided to a Client, such as audiovisual recordings and other test data related to tests and projects you may have participated in, which shall be retained for at least one year from the date of the finalization of the contractual agreement we have with the applicable client of USERLYTICS™. You may also object to our processing of your personal data or ask that we restrict the processing of your personal data in certain instances. If you wish to do any of these things, please contact us at dpo@userlytics.com

### 11\. Children’s Privacy. 

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, USERLYTICS™ does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 16 without parental consent. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 16 without parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 16, please contact us at **dpo@userlytics.com**

### 12\. Links to Other Websites.

You acknowledge, understand and agree that USERLYTICS™ does not have control over any third party website or software or software prototype for which you provide testing services or for which the Website may link to. USERLYTICS™ will not be responsible or liable, directly or indirectly for any damage or loss caused or alleged to be caused by or in connection with the use of or reliance on any such content, products or services available on such other websites or software or software prototype. 

### 13\. Social Media Widgets: 

Our Site includes social media features, such as the Twitter link and other widgets, that run on our Site. These features may collect your IP address and which page you are visiting on our Site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. 

### 14\. Changes to Our Privacy Policy.

All changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.   
If you have any questions about this Privacy please contact us **dpo@userlytics.com**

#### Data Controller Information:

**Company name:** Userlytics Corporation   
**Address:** 700 Lavaca, Suite 1400. Austin, Texas (USA)  
**Phone Number:** +1 512 599 9177, ext 1000  
**Contact email:** dpo@userlytics.com

#### Other cover entities:

User Testing International SL (Spain)
